CHUKWUKA EZE

Benin City, Nigeria · +234-916-021-2133 · ezechuka9@gmail.com · www.linkedin.com/in/iameze/

I've 2+ years of experience in building applications on the Android platform, and I strive to provide the best user experience possible. My focus is on performance, minimalistic user interfaces, clean & efficient code. As a software engineer, I'm driven to influence the customer positively and how my work impacts them. Also, I'm very passionate about the Open-source space and I actively contribute to Open source software (OSS).

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

lvy wallet, Github March 2022 - Present

Android Developer

• Contributed to the open source repository by fixing bugs.

Easychop May 2021 - Nov 2021

Android Developer

- Able to convert UI prototypes into design screens.
- Writing clean & efficient code with best architectural practices & TDD principles.
- Built the easychop delivery app.
- Optimised image loading across the android app by applying caching techniques which lead to reduced memory and bandwidth usage and improved performance.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

WeatherWhiz - Weather forecast mobile app

Aug 2020 - Sept 2020

Android Developer

- Made use of some of Android's latest development tools/principles such as Navigation components, Hilt, etc.
- Made API calls with Retrofit library to fetch data from OpenWeatherMap API.
- Successfully deployed to Google Play Store.

Jamb360 - CBT Mobile App

Jan 2019 - Dec 2019

Android Developer

- Efficiently made SQL queries to the SQLITE DB embedded in the application.
- Successfully deployed to Google Play Store.

EDUCATION

University of Benin Expected Graduation: 2022

Major: Bachelor of Engineering, Computer Engineering

Bachelor of Electrical Engineering

• **Relevant Coursework**: Telecommunication principles, Assembly language programming, Introduction to Software Engineering, Control system theory, Computer architecture and organisation, Engineering mathematics, Data Structures and Algorithms

SKILLS & OTHERS

Skills: Kotlin, Java, Git, GitHub, MVP, MVVM, Dagger-Hilt, Mockito, JUnit, Google Truth, Kotlin Coroutines/Flow, REST APIs, Compose, Retrofit, Jetpack libraries, Googling..

Achievements: Among the top 5 participants in Sauce code Hackathon 2020 edition and ranked in the top 20 of OSCA's open source challenge, 2021.